Inventory of the Daniel Edward Griffiths papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1965-1984 (Box 53)
  - "A New Place in the University for Schools of Education,", 1967 January 16 (Folder 53: 2)
  - "Administrative Theory,", 1984 November (Folder 53: 3)
- Subject file, 1947-1985 (Box 54)
  - Administrators workshop, Plainview, New York, 1963 (Folder 54: 1)
  - Ohio School Boards Association conference, Columbus, Ohio, 1963 (Folder 54: 2)
  - State Federation of District Boards of Education workshop, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1963 (Folder 54: 3)
  - Hofstra School Board conference, Hempstead, New York, 1963 (Folder 54: 4)
  - Council of School Superintendents meeting, Grossinger, New York, 1963 (Folder 54: 5)
- State Federation of District Boards of Education workshop, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1962 (Folder 54: 6)
  - Workshop for principals, Hagerstown, Maryland, 1961 (Folder 54: 7)
  - Central New York School Board Institute meeting, Syracuse, New York, 1963 (Folder 54: 8)
  - New York State Elementary Principals Conference, Syracuse, New York, 1963 (Folder 54: 9)
  - Administrative Work Conference, Bloomington, Indiana, 1961 (Folder 54: 10)
  - Institute on College and University Administration, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1961 (Folder 54: 11)
  - Superintendents Work Conference, Columbia University, New York City, 1962 (Folder 54: 12)
  - Institute on College and University Administration, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1962 (Folder 54: 13)
  - Advanced seminars in administration, Detroit, Michigan, 1962 (Folder 54: 14)
  - Workshop, University of Pittsburgh, 1962 (Folder 54: 15)
  - Capital Area School Boards Institute meeting, Albany, New York, 1962 (Folder 54: 16)
  - Bucks County Elementary Principal Association conference, 1963 (Folder 54: 17)
  - New York University, 1973-1977 (Box 55)
    - Faculty salaries, 1973 (Folder 55: 1)
    - Investiture of President John C. Sawhill, 1975 (Folder 55: 2)
    - Intercollegiate task force, 1977 (Folder 55: 3)
  - Hospital administrators conference, 1962 (Folder 56: 1)
  - New York State Deans and Counselors Association workshop, Sagamore, New York, 1962 (Folder 56: 2)
  - Council of School Superintendents meeting, Kamesha Lake, New York, 1962 (Folder 56: 3)
  - Seminar in administration, University of Toronto, 1962 (Folder 56: 4)
  - Seminar for school administrators, State University of Iowa, Iowa City, 1962 (Folder 56: 5)
  - Institute for School Administrators, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1963 (Folder 56: 6)
  - Detroit Seminar for Advanced Administrative Study, Detroit, Michigan, 1963 (Folder 56: 7)
  - Principals' conference, Northern Illinois University, DeKalb, Illinois, 1963 (Folder 56: 8)
  - Phi Lambda Theta meeting, New York City, 1963 (Folder 56: 9)
  - Elementary principals' workshop, Lehigh University, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1963 (Folder 56: 10)
  - Senior Seminar in Administration, University of Toronto, 1963 (Folder 56: 11)
  - National Symposium on Partnerships in Education, Washington, D. C., 1985 (Folder 57: 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1964-1989 (Folder 57:)
  - "The Improving Quality of Public Education,", 1983 July 17 (Folder 57: 2)
  - "Public Education: America, 1985,", 1985 May 20 (Folder 57: 3)
  - "The Role of a College of Education in a Research-Centered University,", 1985 March 8 (Folder 57: 4)
  - "Advice to the New Principal,", 1983 November 24 (Folder 58: 1)
  - "The Professorship Revisited,", 1984 January 20 (Folder 58: 2)
  - "Educational Administration: The State of the Art,", 1984 July 31 (Folder 58: 3)
  - "Organizational Theory,", 1984 August (Folder 58: 4)
  - "Lead Me and Leave Me Alone,", 1985 February 28 (Folder 58: 5)
  - Commencement address, Central Connecticut State College, 1964 June 7 (Folder 59: 1)
  - "Leadership for Educational Change,", 1964 September 28 (Folder 59: 2)
  - "Administrative Theory,", 1985 January (Folder 59: 3)
  - "Can There Be a Science of Organizations?", 1983 April 7 (Folder 59: 4)
  - "Theories: Past, Present, and Future,", 1982 August (Folder 59: 5)
  - "The Uses of Theory,", 1983 November (Folder 59: 6)
  - "Reflections on 35 Years of Study,", 1985 January 10 (Folder 59: 7)
  - "Educational Administration: Reform PDQ or RIP,", 1988 April 7 (Folder 59: 8)
  - "Where Are the Administrators in the Reform Movement?", 1989 April 28 (Folder 59: 9)
  - Report on a visit to Portland State University, 1989 August (Folder 59: 10)
- Sound recordings, 1983 (Box 59)
  - Compact sound cassette containing an interview of Daniel E. Griffiths, 1983 May 2 (Folder 59: 11)
  - Compact sound cassette containing a speech by Daniel E. Griffiths, "The Improving Quality of Education,", 1983 July 17 (Folder 59: 12)
- Writings and reports on education, 1975-1987 (Box 60)
  - Articles, 1981-1983 (Folder 60: 1)
  - Reports, 1985-1987 (Folder 60: 2-5)
  - "A Study of the Writings of Daniel E. Griffiths" by W. Warren Hay, 1975 (Folder 60: 6)